#### Contact

17194390975 (Home) toddf73@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/todd-farina-mha-bsn-rn-37077940 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**BLS** 

Healthcare

Healthcare Management

### Certifications

CEN

# Todd Farina, MHA, BSN, RN

Director of Emergency Service Departments within Northwest Texas Health System

Amarillo, Texas

### Summary

Dynamic Executive leader who focuses on associate empowerment, leadership development, engagement and patient satisfaction/ experiences. My key principles include: 1. Make work fun, entertaining, exciting; challenge others to reach their potentials. 2. Elevate and support those around you. 3. Follow your passion! 4. Always remember the reason why you "do what you do" 5. Make people smile even at their worse.

## Experience

Northwest Texas Health System -UHS
Director for Emergency Services: Acute care/ER and free standing ER
February 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)
Texas

Sunnyside Community Hospital & Clinics Director of Emergency/ICU Services February 2016 - February 2017 (1 year 1 month) Yakima Valley, WA

Centura Health
Director Of Clinical Services/ER
August 2013 - April 2016 (2 years 9 months)
St. Anthony's

Penrose Hospital
11 years 7 months

Interim ED manager/Assistant Nurse Manager June 2006 - August 2013 (7 years 3 months)

Staff RN/Charge RN February 2002 - June 2006 (4 years 5 months) Tampa General Hospital trauma I: Charge RN June 1994 - June 2002 (8 years 1 month) Tampa, Florida

## Education

University of Phoenix MHA, MHA;BSN · (2011 - 2015)